Sukanya Saha

■ sukanyasaha007@gmail.com

+91 9038416059 ♥ 21, Munshi Zeller Rahim Lane, Salkia Howrah-711106 in



Sukanya



Three years of industrial experience as a data scientist with strong background in predictive model building, data analysis, computer programming, mathematics, statistics and algorithms.

Strengths include commitment to provide support and essential information about trends to companies in a variety of industries, building and presenting models that fit the problem best.

Finely-tuned logical skills with a commitment to elevate subject knowledge and workplace competencies through continuing exploration and training; enthusiastically shoulder additional accountability to ensure optimum and appropriate project accomplishment.



Machine Learning & Deep Learning Algorithms-

Regression, K-Means Clustering, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Principal Component Analysis, Naïve Bayes

Programming Language-

Python-

Machine Learning Libraries - Scikit Learn, Pandas, NumPy, H2O, Dask,

Visualization Libraries- Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly

Deep Learning Libraries- TensorFlow, Pytorch, Keras

Web Scrapping- Selenium, Scrapy, Beautiful Soup

Web Tools - Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C and Prototyping

Amazon web services- Deployed Machine Learning Models into production environment using AWS EC2 instances, Python Boto3 Library

Tools and Version Control - Jupyter Notebooks, Spyder, Docker, Visual Studio Code, R Studio, Git and Bit **Bucket**



Work Experience

Assistant Manager in Decision Sciences, HSBC

March, 2019 - Present

- Predict Credit Card Utilization of Customers to generate offers to increase Credit Limits
- Customer Attrition using Hybrid Machine Learning Model using Random Forest and Gradient Boosting with 92% performance
- Resume Screening using Optical Character Recognition, Text Summarization to help organization save significant amount on resource hiring
- CCTV Surveillance in ATMs using Convolution Neural Network and Activity recognition to reduce criminal activities and fraud in ATMs
- Using web scraping extract Customer reviews from Play Store and Apple Store

- Android and Apple Store Banking Apps Comparison using customer reviews and Topic Modelling to help bank stay updated of customers preference and sentiments among other competitive banking apps available
- Build Flask Based Web Application to Compare Banking apps according to user location using Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Fund Usage Optimization using Market Mix Modelling
- Chatbot using Natural Language Processing and its UI using Flask

Data Scientist, Cognizant Technology Solutions

August, 2016 – February, 2019

- Built Customer Return to Purchase model with 91% Accuracy and scaled up to run the model on weekly basis
- Monthly Updated Model to predict Customer Future Value and Customer Life Cycle Value with 85% performance on highly unbalanced data
- Built Customer Segmentation Model to divide customers to high, medium and low potential groups
- Developed Campaigns for Marketing Analytics team with 5% Sales Improvement
- Using Customer Feedbacks built sentiment Analysis Model Using Natural Language Processing
- Developed model on **Customer Churn** in High Dimensional Data with **94%** Accuracy
- Delivered Weekly report Customer Penetration and Product Inventory in highly disorganized data
- Detected failing servers on a network from the measure of throughput and latency of response- Using Elliptic Envelope, Isolation Forest fitted a Gaussian distribution on data points and Identified Anomaly in servers with a threshold-based approach
- Designed and developed **Machine Learning Framework** for regression and classification models in Python using Scikit learn Numpy and Pandas.
- Built automated solution -Trigger Generation for targeting customers portfolio, product holdings etc.
- Customer Financial Behavior Prediction to offer Term Deposits, Investment and Insurance Products
- Attended regular Governance Meeting for Communicating business insights to Clients one of which was the World's Top Vehicle Manufacturer



Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Instrumentation -

West Bengal University of Technology with 9.0 CGPA

August, 2012- July 2016

Machine Learning by Stanford University hosted on Coursera

July, 2018

Deep Learning Specialization by DeepLearning.ai hosted on Coursera

August, 2018



Awards and Certificates

- Honored with "Above and Beyond" Award in Cognizant Technology Solutions
- Ranked 65th (All India Rank) in Indian Engineering Olympiad
- Conducted a 40 Days Training Session with Differently abled children in Indian Institute of Mother and Child
- Honored for being the Department topper in College in multiple semesters
- Presented Seminar organized by Department of Information Technology, Govt. of India in association with Computer Society of India